The story of a perfect boy who had the perfect plan.
Joshua is a drama, thriller, horror film directed by George Ratliff.
The arrival of a newborn girl causes the gradual disintegration of the Cairn family; particularly for 9-year-old
Joshua, an eccentric boy whose proper upbringing and refined tastes both take a sinister turn.
Brad Cairn, played by Sam Rockwell.
Abby Cairn, played by Vera Farmiga.
Joshua Cairn, played by Jacob Kogan.
Hazel Cairn, played by Celia Weston.
Uncle Ned, played by Dallas Roberts.
Chester, played by Michael McKean.
Joshua (also known as The Devil's Child) is a 2007 American
psychological thriller co-written and directed by George Ratliff.
The film stars Sam Rockwell, Vera Farmiga and Jacob Kogan.
Joshua premiered at the 2007 Sundance Film Festival and was released on July
6, 2007, in the United States by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
The film received favourable reviews from critics, with many praising the performances,
atmosphere and the horror elements, but criticism for its plot and characters.
The film explores themes of child abuse, baby, sibling
relationship, nanny, mother-in-law.
The tone is dark and emotional and thought_provoking.